<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Adaptive Slaugther Robots</title><link href="http://markpp.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://markpp.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://markpp.github.io/</id><updated>2017-04-28T17:49:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Robots</title><link href="http://markpp.github.io/robots-are-comming.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-28T17:49:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T17:49:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Mark Philip Philipsen</name></author><id>tag:markpp.github.io,2017-04-28:/robots-are-comming.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Trends and potential of robots&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;P1 Morgen interviews&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dr.dk/p1/p1-morgen/p1-morgen-2017-04-27"&gt;Link til udsendelse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vil robotterne gøre os arbejdsløse?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotterne kommer, og de kan overtage 40 procent af det arbejde, vi laver i dag, står der i en ny rapport fra Innovationsfonden. Men hvad sker der så med samfundsøkonomien? Er vi på vej mod et samfund, hvor halvdelen ikke skal arbejde? Medvirkende: Jens Hauch, cheføkonom og vicedirektør i tænketanken Kraka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio src="../audio/arbejdsløshed.m4a" controls&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;40% af vores arbejdstimer kan blive overtaget af robotter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En ny rapport fra Innovationsfonden viser, at det med den teknologi vi har til rådighed i dag er det faktisk muligt at automatisere 40 procent af samtlige de arbejdstimer, der bliver lagt på det danske arbejdsmarked. Medvirkende: Lars Høngaard Andersen, direktør i Innovationsfonden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio src="../audio/robotter_overtager.m4a" controls&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dansk Erhverv - Vi skal ruste os til robotternes ankomst&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robotterne kommer, og der kommer formentlig mange af dem i en nær fremtid. Robotter har allerede gjort deres indtog på mange produktionsvirksomheder, men meget mere er på vej. Indenfor servicesektoren kan såkaldte humanoide robotter, altså menneskelige robotter, overtage jobs inden for eksempelvis undervisning. Medvirkende: Jens Klarskov, direktør, Dansk Erhverv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio src="../audio/robotternes_ankomst.m4a" controls&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="robots"></category></entry><entry><title>Injection</title><link href="http://markpp.github.io/inject.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-23T17:49:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-23T17:49:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Mark Philip Philipsen</name></author><id>tag:markpp.github.io,2017-01-23:/inject.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Overview of the selection process for brine injection project&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Adaptive brine injection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brine injection is selected as the basis for a "quick and dirty" project where an adaptive method will help achieve a more optimal addition of salt to meat products. The project's duration is confined to 3-4 month, this means that it is necessary to clearly deliminate the problem and make wide use of "hand held" solutions in order to reduce setup time and quickly test the adaptive method. The adaptiveness lies in measuring the input or the output and controlling the process parameters accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#adaptive-brine-injection"&gt;Adaptive brine injection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#process-description"&gt;Process description&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#initial-experiment"&gt;Initial experiment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#state-of-the-art"&gt;State-of-the-art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#meat-preparation"&gt;Meat preparation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#brine-injection"&gt;Brine injection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tumbling"&gt;Tumbling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#machine-manufacturers"&gt;Machine manufacturers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#process-control-research"&gt;Process control research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#possible-improvements"&gt;Possible improvements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#project-choices"&gt;Project choices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#"&gt;Measuring quality of injection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Process description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brine is added to a wide range of meats before packaging in order to mature and tenderize the meat as well as enhance flavor. The brine consists of water and a mix of salt, phosphate, nitrate, sugar or flavoring. The central ingredient is the salt, which has the effect of increases the solubility of proteins and thereby improve the meats ability to retain water. However, if the salt concentration gets too high, the effect is reversed and the muscle fibers shrink and proteins risk getting washed out. For the best results, the brine should be uniformly distributed throughout the meat. This can be achieved by administering the brine externally or by injecting it directly into the meat. The salt will then diffuse through the meat and distribute evenly, with time, through chemical processes. Salt is able to diffuse at the most 0.5 cm. per day, so if the brine needs to defuse over long distances, it becomes very time intensive and impractical for modern industrial processes.
The standard practice for quickly curing meat is injection of brine using a grid of needles. Even modern injection systems the results are not always satisfactory and the meat is subjected to additional treatments. This extra treatment can happen both before and after the injection of brine. For instance, meat's ability to absorb brine can be improved by hammering before injection, this extends the muscle fibers, which increase room for brine and help achieve a more even distribution. Similarly, accelerated and improved diffusion of the injected brine along with additional absorption can be achieved by further mechanical treatment post-injection. The meat is e.g. massaged, which helps drain pockets of brine and close holes left by the injection needles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapport "Accelereret saltning med multistiksprøjtning" [2] from the the DMRI project; "Optimeret produktion af forædlede kødprodukter" investigates the possibilities for reducing the time needed to salt products using existing equipment. The process can be helped along by treating the meat mechanically. Advanced machinery exists for both injection and mechanical treatment, but no single manufacturer provides a complete state-of-the-art solution and slaughterhouses largely rely on older outdated machinery. The goal of part of the project is to reduce the time usage of the process to under one work day(7 hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The salting process can be be very complex when taking the natural variation of the meat and the process variables into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main process variables are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre-injection mechanical preparation&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The degree to which the muscle fibers are stretched/loosened/opened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Injection pattern&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denseness of injection, i.e. the spacing between injection holes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategy for injecting brine, e.g. continuously, on the down stroke, when reaching the bottom, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brine injection pressure&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brine pressure through the individual needle holes depends on the flow through other holes, which maybe be blocked or completly uncovered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Injection speed/time&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration injecting brine into the meat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-injection mechanical treatment&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Time spend tumbling]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physical properties of the meat that may influence the salting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meat texture&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Hardness and viscosity tells us something about the room around muscle fibers and thereby the meats ability to absorb the brine] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State of muscle fibers e.i. the degree to which the fibers are prepared to absorb the brine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Size and shape&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Especially the height of the meat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Composition&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bone, skin, fat and connective tissue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chemical composition of the brine solution and the chemical properties of the meat effect the salting. The most important chemical variables are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt concentration&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water retention increases with the concentration of salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very high salt concentrations reverses the effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of salt&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;NaCl&lt;/em&gt; is significantly better than &lt;em&gt;KCl&lt;/em&gt; at increasing water retention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar concentration&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar has a similar effect to salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phosphate concentration&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phosphate increases the pH and water retention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pH&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pH decides which ion, &lt;em&gt;Na+&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Cl-&lt;/em&gt;, plays the primary role in increasing water retention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pH value around 6 has shown to lead to optimal water retention when using &lt;em&gt;NaCl&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temperature&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low temperature contributes to better water retention, 4&amp;deg; being optimal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High temperature speeds up the diffusion of salt through the meat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of meat&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amount of protein and the ratios between protein types, e.g. intracellular(soluble) and extracellular(non-soluble), has an effect on the meats ability to retain water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pH difference between cuts , e.g. pork shoulder has a much higher pH than pork loin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Initial experiment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An initial experiment was conducted in order to investigate the effect of the two primary process parameters; brine pressure and injection speed, as well as determine the possibilities for visually measuring the gain using 3D sensing. The details of the experiment are described in &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1raAamsBv-Zgsb5480L5EoHYvCk8Xo8ZGO3J60A4G6CI"&gt;multistiksprøjte eksperiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;State-of-the-art&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meat preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the leading products for mechanical preparation of meat before injection of brine are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;STEAKER/PRESSES by Günther (DE)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MAX by Schröder (DE)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massages the meat in a temperature controlled environment, with or without vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;TwinHammer 5500 by METALQUIMIA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-massaging unit that stretch the muscle fibers, which increase the space around fibrils. Leads to a reduction in the time needed for tumbling after injection.
&lt;a href="http://en.metalquimia.com/products/products-by-family/meat-pre-massaging/twinhammer-5500/"&gt;twinhammer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bladehammer 5500 by METALQUIMIA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.metalquimia.com/products/products-by-family/meat-pre-massaging/bladehammer-5500/"&gt;bladehammer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brine injection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meat industry, brine is most commonly added using machines with multiple injection needles, the number of needles typically ranges from 40 to 500 with a spacing of 12-25 mm. With the trend going towards many thin needles with a high number of small holes combined with high pressure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correct adjustment of the injector has a large impact on the time needed for the salt to properly diffuse. [3]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IMAX 420 by Schröder (DE):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schröder offers integrated weights that automatically control and adapt the injection speed during operation. They also offer individual needle damage and flow detection. Their injection system rely on many and very thin needles as well as independent control of conveyor belt, which allows for a very dense injection pattern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.schroeder-maschinen.de/en/machines/injectors-imax.html"&gt;IMAX 420&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UzfrEysbKYs"&gt;&lt;img alt="Schröder (DE)" src="../images/injection/IMAX_420.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PI 750 DUO by Günther (DE)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spray Plus
Traditionally, brine is injected using needles with a few holes that has a diameter above 1 mm and a low brine pressure of a few bars. With the spray plus system, Günther introduces a spray system where the needles have many holes with a small diameter and a very high brine pressure. This results in very fine droplets that should distribute well in the meat. Because of the much improved distribution of brine, the drip loss is reduced significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classical low pressure injection technique:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="classic_needle_1_2" src="../images/injection/classic_needle_1_2.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(1) Brine injection from the start, (2) Spraying continous as the needles descend&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="classic_needle_3_4" src="../images/injection/classic_needle_3_4.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(3) Needles reach the bottom and leaves pockets of brine, (4) As the needles are withdrawn, brine collects in the holes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="classic_needle_5" src="../images/injection/classic_needle_5.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(5) As the needles leave the meat, brine will escape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new high pressure injection technique:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="spray_needle_1_2" src="../images/injection/spray_needle_1_2.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(1) Needles enters the meat without spraying brine, (2) needles continue al the way to the bottom without spraying&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="spray_needle_3_4" src="../images/injection/spray_needle_3_4.png"&gt;\
&lt;em&gt;(3) Brine is spayed using high pressure from all holes, (4) Needles are withdrawn without spraying brine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficacy of the technology has not been verified independently yet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guenther-maschinenbau.de/en/g-products/pih-300-2-pih-600-4/"&gt;PI 750 DUO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;M3 by FOMACO (DK)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline Weight Controller (IWC) constantly monitors the injection quantity and corrects the settings in case of irregularities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fomaco.com/meat/machines/the-fomaco-m3"&gt;M3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Movistick Plus 5500 by METALQUIMIA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.metalquimia.com/products/products-by-family/spray-meat-injectors-plus/movistick-plus-5500/"&gt;Movistick Plus 5500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;MOVIPLUS 4.0 by METALQUIMIA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.metalquimia.com/products/products-by-family/meat-injectors-moviplus/moviplus-version-40/"&gt;MOVIPLUS 4.0&lt;/a&gt;
Up &amp;amp; Down system for regulating the depth the needles will penetrate in order to avoid injecting fat and skin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8nvVhe9YZHw"&gt;&lt;img alt="up_down" src="../images/injection/up_down.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tumbling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diffusion of salt is helped along by the use of mechanical tumbling, which quickly can distribute the salt up to 2 cm. [3]
The meat is gently tumbled, resulting in a massage of the meat that helps drain unabsorbed brine and thereby avoiding pockets of brine as well as closing up the holes that are left from the injection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DRYBINDER by METALQUIMIA (ES)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DRIPPING TUNNEL by Metalbud Nowicki (PL)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Machine manufacturers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;Country&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;Pre-injection&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;Injection&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;Post-injection&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Metalbud Nowicki&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;Poland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.metalquimia.com/"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;METALQUIMIA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;Spain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.metalquimia.com/"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Marel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;Island&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://marel.com/"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GAROS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;Sweden&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.garos.net/"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FOMACO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;Denmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fomaco.com/"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Günther&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guenther-maschinenbau.de/en/"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Schröder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;:heavy_check_mark:&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.schroeder-maschinen.de/en/home.html"&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Process control research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Determination of Optimal Process Parameters to Prepare Licorice Extract Micro-particles Using Artificial Neural Network Based Particle Swarm Optimization)[https://github.com/markpp/Paper-notes/blob/master/process%20control/zhang2016determination.md] resume(ongoing)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Hybrid fuzzy logic and pid controller based ph neutralization pilot plant)[https://github.com/markpp/Paper-notes/blob/master/process%20control/naseer2013hybrid.md] resume(ongoing)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Possible improvements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of features that has the potential to improve the process, quality and knowledge of the product in general. Some of the features already exist in machines currently on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased injection cadence could lead to high throughput&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible injector that is easierly integrating in the production line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Injection of in-bone meat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing the number of steps/machines required in to achieve the same result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individualized robotic pre-massaging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjustable injection depth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flow monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finer injection patterns without needing more and tighter packed needles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced injection strategies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoiding areas with bone or non muscle tissue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid reaching extreme local concentrations of salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapt injection to individual and local variation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimal injection wrt. to fiber orientation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the hardness of meat tell something about the ability to absorb brine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas:
- Investigate the parameter space&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each type of meat run experiments to find optimal control parameters based on measurements of the result&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple investigation of the individual parameters or grid search for also investigating interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classifier learns the correlation and predicts result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use ML to predict the optimal process parameters for the individual pieces of meat or even the local area of the meat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to find features that allow for to capture the variation in induvidual pieces of meats?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Learning to learn by gradient descent by gradient descent)[https://arxiv.org/abs/1606.04474]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimating volume/weight from 2D or 3D images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Process optimization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimal preparation of meat for uniform salt distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimal injection for uniform salt distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimal post injection processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PID control of process parameters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Closed-loop controller" src="../images/injection/mss_controller_diagram.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Project choices&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Measuring quality of salting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to do optimization a method for determining the quality of the salting is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CT scanning, use contrast fluid if necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slice and photograph, use contrast fluid if necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Injection of salt-meter electrodes to sample salinity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local increase in weight/volume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drip loss/non-absorbed brine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure firmness -&amp;gt; texture &lt;a href="[link](http://www.shimadzu.com/an/industry/foodbeverages/n9j25k00000d138f.html)"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Uniform external color change)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Firmness of meat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Measuring salt content:
&lt;a href="https://www.alibaba.com/product-detail/High-quality-RHS-28ATC-0-28_60393393403.html"&gt;Salt in brine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://qasupplies.com/ssx-210-salt-meter/"&gt;Salt in meat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two platforms that the project could potentially be based on. The first, is the type of dedicated machine that is currently used in the production out in the slaughterhouses. The alternativ is mounting needles on a industrial robot arm, which atleast initially is thought of as an experimentation platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dedicated injector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industrial multi-injectors have roughly looked the samefor half a century. A large box build around a conveyor belt with rows of injection needles that are moved up and down while the conveyor belts moves the meat forward. An example, although of a very old standard, is available to be used and modified for this project. Depending on the ambitioness of the project, the machine needs to under extensive reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic "chip-tuning"&lt;/strong&gt; focused on existing medium-low tier machines
    * Automation of process parameters using feedback from weighing before and after injection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Basic_chip-tuning" src="../images/injection/basic_chip-tuning.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced "chip-tuning"&lt;/strong&gt; focused on existing top tier machines&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic switching between recipes based on detection of meat type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local adjustment of brine based on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Advanced_chip-tuning" src="../images/injection/advanced_chip-tuning.png"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Robot cell injector&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robot cell&lt;/strong&gt; for experimentation, specifically determining local absorption properties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local injection of brine followed by weighing in order to determine local gain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robot cell&lt;/strong&gt; solution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highly customized injection patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High flexibility in application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic cleaning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Local injection experiment" src="../images/injection/local_injection_experiment.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: DMRI report 2014: Optimeret produktion af forædlede kødprodukter, Tomas Jacobsen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2]: DMRI report 2017: Optimeret produktion af forædlede kødprodukter - Accelereret saltning med multistiksprøjtning, Mikael Bülow Pedersen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3]: Bøgh-Sørensen, L. &amp;amp; Zeuthen, P. (2002) Konserveringsteknik bind 2, 2. udgave. DSR Forlag.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="brine"></category><category term="injection"></category></entry><entry><title>Research areas</title><link href="http://markpp.github.io/research-areas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-23T17:49:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-23T17:49:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Mark Philip Philipsen</name></author><id>tag:markpp.github.io,2017-01-23:/research-areas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Overview of the research areas that are of relevance to my PhD&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Reinforcement learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appropriate actions in a given state are learned from feedback in the form of rewards and penalties. Exploration and exploitation are the mechanisms for trying new actions and for xx, respectively.
- Self-learning framework which can be applied to several similar robot control problems. &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1312.5602"&gt;DeepMind, Playing Atari with Deep Reinforcement Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidqiu.com:8888/research/nature14236.pdf"&gt;DeepMind, Human-level control through deep reinforcement learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Continuous(online) learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuously adjusting a trained model while in use, based on feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extending a pretrained model with new functionality, e.g. adding an additional class to a classifier without retraining using the original dataset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hybrid intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the tasks that must be automated are too challenging for current machine intelligence to consistently solve at a satisfactory level of performance. Hybrid intelligence where human intelligence is keept in the loop is thus a necessety for the forseable future. When applying hybrid intelligence there exisits two interaction patterns; active learning and hybrid interaction. In the former, human intelligence is only utilized when the machine isn't confident. In the latter both machine and human intelligence is involved in every case. Here the machine propose a solution that the human must accept, modify or reject. 
&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@clarecorthell/hybrid-artificial-intelligence-how-artificial-assistants-work-eefbafbd5334"&gt;Hybrid Intelligence: How Artificial Assistants Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Transfer learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking a model trained for one task and fine-tuning it for use in a related task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="machine learning"></category><category term="deep learning"></category><category term="reinforcement learning"></category><category term="transfer learning"></category><category term="continuous learning"></category></entry></feed>